

# MATT OSGOOD

#### Marketing Director

Evidence based commercial marketing executive with both client and agency side operational experience (Brand, FMCG, NPD Innovation, eCommerce, Impulse, Acquisition, Retention, Campaigns) in the UK, Ireland, Europe, Canada and USA.

Consistent track record of delivering brand, product and marketing transformation to capture consumer attention and generate advocacy to grow the customer base, drive market share and deliver value to shareholders. Video case study and results of product relaunch EuroMillions #ShareTheDream <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PN85hfN5Ds4">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PN85hfN5Ds4</a>

Skill set grounded in interpreting consumer data insights to inform innovation and engagement, to stimulate behaviour change and sustained LTV growth. Experienced in leading and motivating cross functional, multi-national campaign and project teams, building capability, to deliver commitment from stakeholders and ultimately lower CPAs / accelerate profits.

#### SKILLS & KEY COMPETENCIES

DTC / Consumer Acquisition / Evidenced Based Marketing Strategy / Brand and Marketing Transformation / Change Management Business Planning / Innovation and NPD Concept Testing / RFP and Bid submissions / Research / Brand Architecture / Agency Selection, Management, Remuneration / Creative and Content Development / Process and Ways of Working Improvement / Team Leadership and C-Suite Engagement / Consumer Engagement / Campaign Planning, ROI and applied Econometrics / Advertising / Media Planning / Market Assessment / Workshop Facilitation / Product Launches

#### CAREER EXPERIENCE

**LOTTOLAND.CO.UK** (Category disrupting provider of betting on lottery, bingo and gambling verticals through digital portals)

### **UK Marketing Director**

Oct 2019 - Current

Responsible for UK P&L, growth strategies, brand and portfolio range transformation, research, marketing comms, agency selection & management, product launches, customer acquisition, incubation & CRM.

Delivered best ever acquisition and trading quarter for UK, and best ever performing new product launch.

**CAMELOT GROUP** (Commercial operator of regulated National and State lotteries)

#### **Head of Brand and Marketing, Camelot Global**

2010 - 2019

Responsible for market assessments, brand and marketing for international operations, agency management and selection, consumer research, brand, portfolio and marketing transformation strategies to accelerate growth – including:

### **Director of Consumer Marketing, Camelot Illinois**

2018

- Established new structures, processes, recruited agencies, insight and data requirements, team recruitment and skilling up for operational business transformation takeover, developing FY19 Brand and Marketing Plans
- Growing customer base from 27% in 2018 to 34% of all adults by Jan 2019 and a record \$731m EBITDA in FY19.

#### Head of Marketing, The National Lottery, Ireland

2016

- Led a small but agile team in a highly competitive marketplace, controlling a €20m+ marketing budget across all brands and digital channels for a €700m+ category. Responsible for research, marketing comms, agency management, product and channel launches, consumer PR and customer acquisition
- Drove departmental integration and morale via restructuring Marketing and PR function, introducing new processes and ways of working to better align with the new channels, media landscape and consumption patterns
- Enhanced marketing effectiveness, introducing econometric model and ROI driven approach to advertising and social
   Significantly contributing to the following results:
  - +12% YoY sales growth (+9.6% in Retail / +78.3% YoY in Digital) fastest growing lottery in Europe in 2016
  - Best Lotto sales in past 5yrs and Best EuroMillions sales in past 10yrs Best Ever sales on Instants and Xmas Raffle
  - Reversed 6-year decline growing customer base to 66% of all adults (+8 YoY)
  - Grew 18-24-year-old this hard to reach customer base from 38% in Jan 2016 to 55% by Jan 2017
  - Successful launches of TNL Twitter account and Android/iOS transactional App

- Improved position of #51 (from #81 in prior year) in the annual Ireland RepTrak® study corporate reputation score
- Presented this work as a case study to the North American Association of Lotteries NASPL conference in 2017.

### + Consulting Engagements while Head of Brand and Marketing at Camelot Global include:

#### Marketing Consultant to the Arkansas Scholarship Lottery

2016 - 2019

• Long term consulting to Advertising Director to improve marketing effectiveness and turnaround trading, helping deliver 26% growth in profits since 2015, plus Best Ever sales in FY18 and again in FY19.

#### Portfolio Product Pipeline and Brand Consultant to Camelot UK

2017

• Supported UK 2017 strategic review of commercial plans to revive trading, focusing on Portfolio evolution and Brand.

### Product Innovation Consultant and Project Lead to the EuroMillions community

2014 - 2015

- Led cross functional project team to develop the 2016 NPD options to deliver innovation across 10 European markets
- Partnered with French counterpart, to develop and facilitate 5-year strategic roadmap workshops for community CFOs.

### **Marketing Consultant to the New York lottery**

2013 - 2014

Conducted agency review and advised review committee on \$90m p.a. Creative and Media Agency 2014 RFP pitch.

# Product Innovation Consultant and Project Lead to the Interprovincial Lottery Corporation, Canada 20

2011 - 2012

• Led project team of executives from the ILC and the 5 Canadian lotteries, to deliver an insightful informed, quantified game innovation process – resulting new game launched successfully in 2013.

# **Advertising Consultant to the California lottery**

2009 - 2011

- Selected from Camelot UK as part of a cross functional team to conduct a business review, drafting FY11-FY13
  Business Plan marketing strategies; providing on-going advertising and media planning consulting to step change
  trading helping California become the fastest growing US lottery in FY11 (+13% YoY) and again in FY12 (+27% YoY)
- Selection committee review member on \$50m p.a. Creative and Media Agency 2010 RFP pitch.

#### **Camelot UK**

### Elected Chair of Marketing Workgroup of the European Lotteries participating in EuroMillions

2008 - 2010

Coordination of the 10 lotteries (20 persons, 9 nationalities, 5 languages), responsible for development of strategic annual plans at European level, reporting to Directors of the 10 lotteries

• Led a cross functional community team to review, develop and research the 2011 relaunch, gaining Director and CEO sign-off on the recommended innovations across the community - growing sales to over €7bn (+63% YoY).

### **EuroMillions Marketing Manager**

2007 - 2010

Responsible for UK EuroMillions brand strategy, research, product innovation, TTL advertising and media ROI optimisation of annual £10m+ marketing budget.

- Grew customer base by +105% to 17m UK adults driving sales to become TNL's third £1bn+ game
- Developed and launched Millionaire Raffle the most successful new game innovation for revenues since 1997.

#### **Product Manager**

2005 - 2007

• Annual brand plans and multi-channel activation for Lotto, EuroMillions and launch of Lottery@till with Tesco.

### **Previous Organisations**

•	HS&P - Account Director on The National Lottery	2003 – 2005
•	Mediator – freelance Account Director on Freeserve	2003
•	White Door – freelance Account Director on British Telecom	2002
•	Burkitt DDB – Account Director on Birra Peroni, ITV Popstars, Drambuie, RHS	2000 – 2002
•	ZGC – Senior Account Manager on Kodak, Scottish Courage, Wall's Ice Cream	1999 – 2000
•	MHP – Account Manager on Kodak, Wall's Ice Cream, CCSB	1995 – 1999

### **EDUCATION**

BA Hons: Economics and Politics - University of Hertfordshire. A Levels: Business Studies, Economics, Law

## **A**wards

The Marketing Institute of Ireland - Mobile Marketing 2017, The Media Awards - Best Use of Media 2017, Accenture Digital Media Awards - Best Creative 2017, The Marketing Society Excellence Awards - Advertising Research 2016, eir Spiders Digital Awards - Best Campaign 2016, Checkout National FMCG Awards - Best New Product Launch 2016, IPA Effectiveness Award -

2012, Media Week Awards - Best use of Econometrics 2011, Thinkbox TV Planning Awards - Best ongoing use of TV 2011, World Lottery Association Biennial Advertising Awards - Grand Global Award 2010, MCCA Best Awards - Best Multi-Disciplined Campaign 2002, Media Week Awards - Best Sponsorship & Grand Prix 2001